[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 13]
[제13화]
I was a bit distracted just now.
잠시 생각에 잠겼다
Sorry about that.
실례하였구나
Alright.
예
Well,
저기...
how did you know I was looking for someone?
사형은 제가 사람을 찾는 걸 어떻게 아셨습니까?
I'm sharp as a tack
그게 내가 귀가 밝고 눈이 좋아서
and always well-informed.
소식도 빠르다
You're the new disciple from Zhuiyu Peak, right?
너는 추옥봉에 새로 온 소사매로구나
I heard you have lots of snacks.
네가 맛있는 걸 많이 가졌다고 들었다
Do you have any left?
또 있느냐?
Share some with me.
내게 하나 주어라
Um...
저게
Lifei.
려비
I've given them all out today.
오늘은 다 나누어 주었습니다
I'll bring some for you next time.
다음에 가져올게요
Remember to save some for me next time!
다음엔 꼭 나에게도 주어라
Remember my name!
내 이름을 꼭 기억하여라
I'm Deng Xiguang!
나는 등계광이다
I've searched all sixteen peaks.
열여섯 개의 봉을 다 찾아보았는데
Senior Brother!
대사형!
Where are you?
도대체 어디 계십니까?
Coming!
왔다, 왔다
What's wrong?
무슨 일이에요?
Someone has broken the restriction spell.
누군가 추옥봉 금제를 침범하였다
Zhaomin wants us to search
사저가 우리더러 여기저기 살펴
for the intruder.
도둑이 어디 있는지 찾아보라고 하였다
Restriction spell?
금제?
Lifei.
려비
Senior brothers!
대사형
The intruder is here!
도둑이 여기에 있습니다
Senior brothers!
사형
The intruder is here!
도둑은 여기 있다고요
The records of disciples' origins from all peaks
각 봉 제자의 신상과 이력을 적은 명부는
are kept in the Huanyue Shrine
모두 문곡전 뒤 환월사 안에
behind Wengu Hall.
보관되어 있어
I'll wait for you there.
내가 거기서 기다릴게
Lifei!
소사매
where's the intruder?
도둑이 어디 있느냐?
My mistake.
착각입니다, 착각
It was a cricket.
귀뚜라미였어요
Go back to your duties.
대사형 일이나 하세요
Go... go catch the intruder.
도, 도둑을 잡아야지요
- Go ahead. - Let's go.
- 가자 - 가요
You're always running around.
매일 돌아다니기만 하네
Getting lost elsewhere is one thing.
딴 데서 길 잃은 건 그렇다 치고
But if you get lost near Wengu Hall,
만약 문고전 근처에서 길을 잃으면
the night winds there
그 밤의 천풍은
might kill you because they're colder than winter frost.
겨울 서리 칼날보다 더 살을 에는 듯하다
Even the guards won't go there.
수위조차 가지 않는 곳이다
Only a fool would wait all night.
바보가 아니고선 밤새워 기다리겠어?
He's no fool.
바보가 아닌데
He must have left.
분명히 갔을 것이야
Another pity play. I don't believe it.
또 고육지책이냐? 누가 믿겠어?
Huanyue Shrine is a restricted area for the sect.
환월사는 문종의 중요한 곳이니
Unauthorized disciples are not allowed to enter.
관계없는 제자는 함부로 들어갈 수 없다
Senior brothers,
사형님들
I'm here on my master's orders.
저는 사부의 명으로 왔습니다
I need to look up some sect records.
본문의 권종을 좀 조사하러요
Oh, you're from Cuihua Peak.
아, 취화봉에서 왔구나
Senior sister,
사매
did Qin send you?
진 사형이 오라고 하였느냐?
Yes, him.
진 사형, 맞습니다
Then it's fine.
그럼 문제없다
Please come in.
사매, 들어오너라
Who's there?
누구냐?
Hushe Peak.
호사봉
Hushe Peak?
호사봉?
What are you doing here again?
또 왜 온 것이야?
If you really want to make it up to me,
정말 나에게 보상하고 싶다면
just stay out of my sight.
내 눈앞에 나타나지 마
I still have something to finish.
아직 끝내지 못한 일이 있어
What are you plotting now?
또 무슨 꿍꿍이야?
Trust me one more time.
한 번만 더 나를 믿어
Trust you, my foot.
믿긴 뭘 믿어
Stop following me.
따라오지나 마
If we're caught,
만약 들키면
we'll both be expelled from Wuyue Court.
반드시 함께 무월정에서 쫓겨날 거야
Forget it.
됐어
I'm going back.
나도 돌아갈게
Your master already knows.
네 사부께서 이미 아셨어
Take care of yourself.
알아서 해
Master.
사존님
You truly are exceptionally gifted.
역시 너는 타고난 자질이 뛰어나구나
In just a few days,
온 지 얼마 되지 아니하여
you've been able to break the restriction spells.
각 봉의 금제를 열 수 있다니
I value talent.
내가 인재를 아끼기는 하나
But if your mind is distracted
만약 네가 마음이 산란하거나
and your conduct is improper,
품행이 단정치 못하다면
Yaoguang Peak will not keep you.
요광봉도 너를 두지 않겠다
I know my mistake.
제자가 잘못을 알았습니다
This is the Danxue secret realm.
이것이 바로 단혈 비경이다
Only disciples who have reached the third level of cultivation
오직 수련이 제 삼 층에 도달한 제자만이
can leave here.
나갈 수 있도다
What you learned before was broad but not focused.
네가 전에 배운 건 많지만 제대로 아는 건 없다
Your spirit aura is chaotic.
영식이 뒤죽박죽이었지
If you can't let go of greed and worldly attachments
만약 탐욕과 속세의 생각을 버리지 못하고
and purify your spirit and essence,
정신을 단단히 하고 골수를 정화하지 못한다면
you will stay in there for the rest of your life.
평생 그 안에 있게 될 것이다
Gather the Qi in the vessel
기를 정에 모아
and merge it with heaven and earth.
천지에 합류시키고
Transform Qi into spirit
기로 영을 만들며
and command all things!
만물을 부리느니라
Among Wuyue Court's sixteen peaks,
무월정 십육 봉 중에
there is no Hushe Peak.
호사봉은 없다
Right.
그러하다
None of us has ever seen Hushe Peak.
우리는 호사봉을 본 적이 없다
Lifei,
소사매
where did you hear about it?
어디서 들은 것이냐?
I've searched every peak
모든 봉우리를 다 찾아보았지만
and couldn't find my senior brother.
대사형을 못 찾았어요
I'm getting anxious.
마음이 너무 급해서 그런 겁니다
Come here.
사형, 이리 오세요
Here.
그게
Besides
혹시
the southwest corner of Baicao Peak,
백초봉 남서쪽 모퉁이 말고
are there any other peaks?
다른 들봉은 없습니까?
Never seen one.
못 보았다
Oh,
아
you haven't been to Cuihua Peak yet, right?
취화봉에 아직 안 갔지?
It has never allowed unauthorized entry by disciples of other peaks.
취화봉은 타 봉 제자의 출입을 절대 허락하지 않는다
If you want Elder Cuixuan to use Lifei to temper his sword,
취현 장로께서 소사매로 검을 제사 지내게 하고 싶으면
by all means, encourage her to go.
계속 부추겨 보아라
The third level of Wuyue Court's techniques.
무월정 공법 제 삼 층은
Spirit energy floods the meridians;
영이 경락에 흐르고
cultivator and sword become one.
인검이 하나가 되는 경지다
The Danxue secret realm
단혈 비경은
is actually a state of mind.
실은 마음의 경지다
Unless the inner demon is removed,
심마를 없애지 않으면
the formation will never break.
법진을 깨지 못하느니라
Inner demon?
심마
Kill.
죽어라
Did Lei Xiuyuan get punished by his master?
뇌수원이 사부께 벌받은 것이 아니겠지?
None of my business.
나와 무슨 상관이야?
Don't think about him.
생각하지 말자
The technique is incomplete.
술법이 아직 완성되지 않아
She will still feel pain.
려비는 여전히 아플 것이다
To walk the world is to hold a torch through endless night.
사람이 살아가는 건 어둠 속에서 횃불 들고 걷는 것과 같다
Your goodwill still lingers,
선한 마음이 아직 남아 있고
and you are bold and resolute,
용감하고 끈기가 있으니
so you may break free from this deadlock.
길을 깨뜨릴 수도 있을 것이다
Remember, what your soul yearns for
기억하라, 마음이 향하는 곳이
is the right path for you.
네가 해야 할 바른 선택이다
What my soul yearns for?
마음이 향하는 곳이라...
I was right about you.
역시 난 사람을 잘 보았구나
You've broken through the third level.
네가 제 삼 층 경지를 돌파하다니
You must have found your heart of cultivation.
이미 자신의 수행하는 마음을 찾은 모양이군
Remember,
기억하라
this heart can overturn heaven and earth.
이 마음은 천지를 뒤집을 수 있고
Even if faced with thunder, fire,
비록 천둥과 불바다라 할지라도
and endless calamity,
끝없는 재앙이라도
it can't be shaken.
조금도 흔들 수 없도다
- Hello. - Hello.
사형, 사제
Heard he broke through the third level in just three days.
겨우 사흘 만에 제 삼 층을 돌파하였다고?
Truly impressive.
정말 대단하구나
No wonder Master values him
사존께서 중히 여기실 만하군
and took him as a direct disciple.
친전 제자로 삼으신 사람은
Truly gifted.
역시 타고난 자질이 뛰어나네
Indeed.
그러게
Congratulations
축하한다, 사제
on your advancement.
수련이 크게 늘어
You've broken through the third level.
제 삼 층 돌파에 성공하였다
Before you,
이전에는
only Hu Jiaping had done it.
호가평 호 사형만이 해내셨다
That traitor!
호가평 그 배신자
Bewitched by an artifact spirit,
겨우 한 기령 때문에
he lost his mind and defied Master.
색에 현혹되어 사부님을 거역하다니
He's brought shame to Yaoguang Peak.
우리 요광봉에 수치를 끼쳤다
Well said.
사형 말씀이 맞소
Right.
맞소, 맞소
Hu was Master's direct disciple.
호 사형은 사부님의 친전제자시고
He entered before you.
사형보다 먼저 입문하셨습니다
Speaking ill of your senior
사형이 윗사람을 모욕하다니
is the same as insulting our master.
사부님을 욕보인 것과 같습니다
[Songfeng, Wuyue Court] So what if you broke through
[무월정 송풍] 제 삼 층 돌파했다고 잘난 척하지 말라
You must have used some magical treasure, right?
설마 무슨 보물이라도 쓴 것이냐?
Fine. I'll show you.
좋습니다, 당장 보여주지요
Songfeng,
송풍 사제
you've been here for years
입문한 지 여러 해가 지났건만
and still haven't broken through the second level.
아직 제 이 층도 돌파하지 못하여
Master is already disappointed.
사부님께서 원래 탐탁지 않게 여기신다
I suggest you watch your words.
그러니 말과 행동을 조심하여
Don't upset him further.
사부님의 마음을 상하게 하지 말라
You...
뭐
Go!
가자
Stop staring!
무엇을 보느냐
Songfeng holds grudges.
송풍이라는 자는 뒤끝이 심해서
He probably won't let this go.
아마 가만히 있지 않을 것이다
Let him.
내버려두시오
I thought you had issues with Hu.
네가 호 사형에 대해 불만이 있는 줄 알았더니
Didn't expect you to defend him.
감싸줄 줄은 몰랐네
He taught us.
우리의 선생님입니다
Us?
우리라니?
Jiang Lifei?
강려비?
Crispy skin, tender meat.
껍질은 바삭하고 살은 부드럽구나
Looks delicious.
보기만 해도 맛있겠다
Where is Hushe Peak?
호사봉이 어디 있습니까?
Tell me!
알려 주십시오
I suddenly remembered something.
내가 갑자기 한 가지 일이 생각났구나
I have to go right now.
지금 당장 가보아야겠다
Wait,
아니
can you...?
사부님, 먼저...
Master,
사부님
when will you be back?
언제 돌아오십니까?
I... I don't know exactly.
구체적인 시간은 나, 나도 모른다
But you behave and listen to Zhaomin while I'm gone.
하나 집에서 대사저 말을 잘 들어야 한다
What shameful secret is hidden in there?
뭐 숨길 만한 게 있는 것입니까?
Who says Hushe Peak has a secret to...?
누가 호사봉에 숨긴 게 있다고 하였느냐?
There really is a Hushe Peak, isn't there?
호사봉이 실제로 있긴 한 것이죠?
Actually,
사실은
I know where it is.
그게 어디 있는지 압니다
There's a map of it in Huanyue Shrine.
환월사에 지도가 있습니다
Fine.
알았다, 알았다
I guess
내가 보기엔
no one here can control you anymore.
여기서 너를 제어할 사람이 없구나
You've even gone to Huanyue Shrine!
혼자서 환월사에까지 들어갔다니
If you won't tell me,
사부님께서 말씀하지 않으시면
then I'll go myself.
제가 직접 가겠습니다
Go ahead then.
가 보아라
It has a restriction spell.
거긴 금제가 있거늘
You think you can get in?
가 봐야 들어갈 수 있겠느냐?
Restriction spell?
금제요?
So mysterious.
그렇게 신비롭다니
Could it be...?
설마...
What do you know?
무엇을 아느냐?
Is there treasure in there?
설마 보물이 있습니까?
What treasure, Master?
사부님, 무슨 보물입니까?
How much is it worth?
그 값이 얼마나 됩니까?
A girl shouldn't be so vulgar.
여자가 그렇게 속되게 굴지 말아라
We'll talk when I get back.
됐다, 돌아와서 말하겠다
Master.
사부님
Tell me now.
지금 말해 주십시오
This is urgent.
지금 매우 급하구나
I'm off!
간다
Master!
사부님!
Master.
사부님
Zhaomin's three-sided mirror.
사저는 삼릉경
Master's six-sided mirror.
사부님은 육릉경
They should be able to help me break the restriction spell.
분명 나를 도와 금제를 깰 수 있겠지?
Hushe Peak looks like a mallet.
이 호사봉은 어찌 봉추 같지?
Mr. Hu?
호 선생님
What are you doing here?
어찌 오셨습니까?
Stop looking.
찾지 말라
I am your senior brother.
내가 바로 너의 대사형이다
Hold tight.
꼭 붙잡아라
Or you'll fall.
아니면 떨어질 것이다
Senior Brother?
대사형
You're really my senior brother?
정말 제 대사형입니까?
The one in Master's sketch?
사부님 그림 속의 대사형이란 말입니까?
Don't mention that sketch.
그 그림은 말하지 말라
I'm handsome and elegant.
내가 이렇게 준수하고 풍채가 당당한데
I look nowhere near that ugly.
어찌 초상화처럼 그렇게 못생겼겠느냐?
Senior Brother!
대사형
Why did you only show up now?
어찌 이제야 오셨습니까?
I've been looking for you forever!
정말 오랫동안 찾았습니다
You got snot all over my new clothes.
콧물을 내 옷에 다 묻혔다
Mu made this for me.
이는 아모가 내게 만들어 준 새 옷이다
Look at the mess you made.
네가 묻힌 것 보아라
You're really my senior brother?
정말 제 대사형 맞습니까?
Would I lie to you?
내 너를 속일 수 있겠느냐?
Listen to me.
내 말을 들으라
I still can't believe it.
아직도 믿을 수가 없습니다
I was an orphan too, just like you.
나는 너와 같이 고아였다
After that old man took me in,
사부님이 거둔 후에
I followed him, wandering from place to place.
사부님을 따라 이리저리 떠돌며 살았지
When I grew older
그 후 내가 점점 자라자
and had learned most of his skills,
사부님의 재주도 거의 배웠다
he sent me to Chufeng Academy.
그래서 나를 추봉서원으로 보냈지
Later, I gained the favor of Master Guangwei,
후에 광미 사부님의 총애를 받아
so I went to Wuyue Court.
무월정으로 갔다
And you probably know
그 후의 일은
the rest.
너도 다 안다
Then why didn't you tell me when I asked before?
제가 전에 물었을 때 어찌 말 안 하셨습니까?
You even made things hard for me.
일부러 괴롭히기만 하고
I had no choice.
나도 어쩔 수 없었지
Master said
사부님께서 모두 당부하셨거든
I could never mention this to anyone.
이 일은 누구에게도 말할 수 없다고
Otherwise, both he and I would lose our lives.
그렇지 아니하면 사제의 목숨이 위태롭다고
And
게다가
when did I ever make things hard for you?
내가 언제 너를 괴롭혔느냐?
That was encouragement and motivation.
격려하고 채찍질한 것이지
I meant well.
내가 얼마나 마음을 썼는지 아느냐?
I think you had bad intentions.
심보가 좋지 못한 것이죠
You just wanted to kick me out of the academy!
저를 서원에서 쫓아내려 한 거잖아요
You wronged me.
억울하다
I never wanted to kick you out.
너를 쫓아내려 한 적 없다
The one I wanted to get rid of was Lei Xiuyuan.
내가 쫓아내려 한 것은 뇌수원이다
Why?
어째서요?
Because...
왜냐하면
Because he clearly doesn't look like a good guy.
딱 봐도 좋은 사람이 아니다
I have sharp eyes.
나는 눈이 밝아
I could tell he had ulterior motives toward you.
일찍이 쟤가 너에게 나쁜 마음을 품은 걸 알았지
See?
어른의 말을 듣지 않으면
You didn't listen
분명 손해 볼 거라고들 하잖아
to your elder.
안 그러냐?
Almost got yourself killed, didn't you?
목숨까지 잃을 뻔하지 않았냐?
No.
아니요
That's not right.
수상해
You're definitely hiding something else from me.
분명 저에게 숨긴 일이 있죠?
No, really.
없다, 없대도
Don't overthink things.
매일 함부로 생각하지 말라
You love causing trouble, too.
여전히 쓸데없이 난리 치는군
If it weren't for you,
네가 아니었다면
I wouldn't be
이렇게 늦은 밤에
at Wuyue Court this late.
나도 무월정에 올 일이 없었을 것이다
Right?
안 그러냐?
Jiaping,
사형
do you know where Master is?
사부님이 어디 계시는지 아세요?
Is he being hunted?
누군가에게 쫓기고 있는 것이죠?
Is his life in danger?
생명의 위험이 있습니까?
Master is a hidden expert.
사부님은 이름을 숨긴 고수시라
Ordinary people can't touch him.
보통 사람은 어찌하지 못하신다
An expert?
고수요?
Why would an expert go into hiding?
고수가 어찌하여 이름을 숨기십니까?
He's not some bandit, is he?
설마 강도는 아니시지요?
Maybe he has too many enemies?
원수가 너무 많으셔서?
Can't you wish
그게 말이다
for something good for our master?
우리 사부님 좋은 쪽으로만 생각하자
He must have his reasons
이름을 숨기기로 선택하셨다면
for going into hiding.
반드시 그러한 원인이 있다
If you keep looking around blindly,
네가 이렇게 함부로 찾아다니면
you'll only bring trouble. Understand?
오히려 화를 부를 것이로다, 알겠느냐?
No.
안 됩니다
I need to see with my own eyes that he's safe.
사부님이 무사하신 걸 꼭 확인해야 합니다
Fine, fine.
됐다, 됐다
I'll find him.
사부님 찾는 일은 내게 맡겨라
Your top priority now is to focus on your cultivation.
너의 지금 첫째 목표는 수련에 힘쓰는 것이다
Now that you've become Master Chongyi's disciple,
네가 충이 사숙을 스승으로 모셨으니
study hard under him.
그분을 따라 열심히 배우라
Otherwise, even if you find Master,
그렇지 않으면 사부님을 찾아도
with your current skills,
너의 지금 이 정도 실력으로는
you won't be able to help him anyway.
도울 수 없을 것이다
Is that why Master didn't tell me?
설마 제가 도움이 안 되어서
Because I can't help?
사부님이 제게 아무 말도 하지 않으신 겁니까?
Jiaping.
사형
I need to get stronger.
강해지고 싶습니다
One day, I'll be able to help Master.
언젠가 반드시 사부님을 도울 수 있을 겁니다
Good.
좋다
Since you show such devotion,
네게 그런 효심이 있다면
I'll help you.
내 당연히 도와주리라
Your constitution is unique.
너의 체질은 남과 다르다
So you don't have to follow
그러므로 수련 방식도
the usual methods of cultivation.
평범한 방법을 따르지 않아도 된다
Remember,
기억하라
all spirit energy
천지 영기는
is within your every breath.
모두 네 한 호흡 사이에 있다
Nothing is everything. Emptiness is fullness.
없음이 곧 있음이고 빈 것이 곧 가득한 것이다
Even a flying insect has its own path.
날벌레도 날벌레의 도가 있는 법
Lifei,
소사매
you have a long road ahead.
너의 앞날은 아직 머니까
You'll understand it in time.
스스로 천천히 깨닫도록 하여라
Not a word to anyone about what happened today.
오늘 일은 절대 누구에게도 말하지 말아라
I felt it.
맑고 투명한 영기가
Such pure spirit energy.
느껴집니다
Jiaping...
사형...
Jiaping!
사형
I'm going back to the academy.
난 서원으로 돌아간다
Here's the Mind-Calming Mantra for you.
정심결 한 벌을 남겨주겠다
Stay calm through all changes.
만물이 변해도 마음은 여전히 고요하고
Keep your spirit steady and your mind clear.
정신은 평온하며 기운은 안정되어 있다
Just like Master's disciple.
역시 사부님의 친제자답군
Leaves a letter and disappears. Same bad habit!
책만 남기고 가다니, 똑같아
Wait,
아니
I don't know the way back!
길을 모릅니다
At least take me back first!
저를 먼저 돌려보내셔야죠
Jiaping.
사형
I don't know the way.
전 길을 모른다고요
Is Zhuiyu Peak to the east or west?
추옥봉은 동쪽이야, 서쪽이야?
Lifei.
려비 사매
it's you?
어찌 너냐?
Qin?
진 사형
You're back?
돌아오셨습니까?
Stop following me.
더 이상 따라오지 마
Aren't you Master Chongyi's disciple?
충이 사숙 문하에 있지 않더냐?
Why are you here at night?
어찌 한밤중에 여기 있는 것이냐?
Are you lost?
설마 길을 잃은 것이냐?
Yes.
예, 예
I thought the moonlight was beautiful
이 달빛이 좋아 보여
and just wanted to fly in for a closer look.
좀 더 가까이서 보고 싶었습니다
But the wind was howling,
그런데 바람이 휘몰아쳐
and I got dizzy
어지러워져서 그만...
and ended up here.
여기까지 오게 되었지 뭡니까
Wuyue Court
무월정은
has strong winds and thick fog at night.
한밤중에 바람이 크고 안개가 짙어
Each peak has its own restriction spell.
각 봉에 금제가 설치되어 있으니
You can't wander around.
함부로 들어갈 수 없다
How about I take you back to Zhuiyu Peak?
내가 너를 추옥봉까지 데려다줄까?
Okay. Please.
예, 예, 좋습니다
Thank you so much.
그럼 진 사형께 감사합니다
Hold tight.
꼭 붙잡아라
Lifei doesn't trust others easily.
려비가 그리 쉽게 남을 믿다니
I was worrying for nothing.
내가 정말 쓸데없는 걱정을 했군
Hold tight.
꼭 붙잡아라
Remember now.
생각나거라
Lifei!
려비!
Why those images?
어찌 그런 화면이 떠오르는 거지?
And whose voice was that?
그 목소리는 또 누구일까?
Lifei.
려비
Jiang Lifei!
강려비
Jiang...
강...
What's wrong with her?
어찌 된 것이냐?
What's going on here?
이게 무슨 일이냐?
Lifei started training at dawn.
소사매가 이른 아침부터 수련을 시작하였습니다
Is she finally turning over a new leaf?
잘못을 깨닫고 용기를 낸 것이 아닐까요?
No way. Absolutely not.
아니다, 절대 아닐 거다
Jiang Lifei, stop pretending.
강려비, 나한테 그런 척을 하지 말라
Master. You know what?
사부님, 모르시겠지만
If it weren't for Qin bringing me back
어제 그 진 사형이
yesterday,
저를 데려오지 않았다면
I might never have seen you again.
사부님을 뵙지 못하였을 것입니다
If I'm so useless,
제자가 이렇게 쓸모없다면
that would embarrass you.
사부님의 체면을 손상하는 것이 아닙니까?
For your honor
사부님의 체면을 위하여
and for Zhuiyu Peak's dignity,
우리 추옥봉의 존엄을 위하여
won't you teach me some self-defense techniques?
제게 호신법 몇 가지를 가르쳐 주셔야 하지 않습니까?
Then you...
그러면...
Um, I'll make you meat buns.
저기, 만두, 고기 소 만두로
Fine. I'll teach you one.
좋다, 그럼 하나 가르쳐 주마
But let's be clear. Whether you make it or not
물론 먼저 말해 두겠다, 성공하든 못 하든
depends on you.
너 자신에게 달렸다
Don't just stand there. Go make the food.
아직 멍하니 있느냐? 만두를 만들러 가거라
Right away. Just a moment.
잠시만 기다리십시오, 바로 가겠습니다
I went to the place they mentioned last time.
지난번 그들이 말한 그 가게에 갔는데
I liked it too.
나도 괜찮다고 생각해
Lei Xiuyuan!
뇌수원
They say you're Wuyue Court's
다들 네가 우리 무월정의
once-in-a-century genius.
백 년에 한 번 나올까 한 천재라 하는데
Since we're both free today,
오늘은 할 일이 없으니, 차라리
how about a spar?
한번 겨루어 보지 않겠느냐?
Stop right there!
거기 서라!
You dare destroy my sword?
감히 내 패검을 부수다니
Lei, we're fellow disciples.
뇌 사제, 모두 같은 문중이니
Let's keep things friendly.
화를 내지 말라
Qin.
진 사형
It's been half a year since we parted at the academy.
서원에서 헤어진 지 반년이 되었구나
I heard
뇌 사제가
Master Guangwei took you as his personal disciple.
광미 사숙의 친전제자가 되었다 들었다
Congratulations.
정말 축하하는구나
It's just my master's favor.
사부님께서 과분하게 여겨주신 것뿐입니다
Qin, I have things to do.
진 사형, 볼일이 있으니
I'm leaving.
먼저 가보겠습니다
Look at him, so smug.
저 잘난 척하는 꼴을 보아라
He struts around
단혈에서
just because he broke through the third level
제 삼 층 공법을 이루었다고
at Danxue.
여기저기서 잘난 척하고 다니네
He doesn't even respect Qin.
진 사형마저 무시하다니
Qin, you're known for your exceptional talent.
우리 진 사형의 뛰어난 자질을 모르는 사람이 있겠습니까?
You're about to break through the fifth level.
곧 제 오 층 공법을 돌파하실 것이지요
Having a rising star like Lei
뇌 사제와 같은 후배가 있음은
is a blessing for Wuyue Court.
무월정의 복이다
Songfeng, I need to see Master Guangwei.
사제, 광미 사숙을 찾을 일이 있으니
I'm leaving.
먼저 가보겠다
If it weren't for Qin,
진 사형이 아니었다면
I'd have taught him a lesson.
내 진작 뇌수원을 때렸을 것이다
Wu Nuo is just an outer sect disciple.
오낙은 산 아래 외문 제자에 불과하여
He is of low cultivation, utterly insignificant.
수련이 낮아 말할 것도 없었다
Why did it take you so long
어찌하여 제압하는데
to subdue him?
그렇게 오랜 시간이 걸렸느냐?
Sir, that traitor was secretly practicing demonic techniques.
사숙님, 그 배신자가 몰래 마족 사법을 수련하였습니다
He went mad
미친 듯이
and killed his fellow disciples.
동문 사형제를 해치고
He absorbed their spirit power,
사형제들의 영력을 모두 흡수하였습니다
which greatly boosted his cultivation.
이에 따라 수련이 크게 늘었습니다
I had to use my master's
제자가 사존님께서 전해주신 보물
Yin-Yang Tribulation Mirror
음양겁파경을 사용하여
to barely restrain him.
겨우 제압하였습니다
How could an immortal sect disciple know demonic techniques?
선문 제자가 어찌 마족 공법을 아느냐?
Have you found out why?
원인을 조사하였느냐?
There's no right or wrong in techniques. Power is the only truth.
공법에 옳고 그름은 없도다, 힘이 곧 정의로다
Think it over. You can hand it in
잘 생각하거라, 바칠 수도 있고
or not.
바치지 않을 수도 있도다
I searched for days but found nothing.
제가 여러 날 조사하였으나 단서를 찾지 못하였습니다
Perhaps he was bewitched by the demons.
아마 마족 요인에게 현혹된 것 같습니다
I've heard of similar incidents
제가 듣기로 다른 선문에서도
occurring in other sects.
비슷한 일이 발생하였다 합니다
It seems the demons want to overthrow the Central Plains
아마 마족이 중토를 뒤엎고
and divide the immortal sects.
선문을 분열시키려는 것입니다
That's possible.
그럴 가능성이 있다
Demons have always been cunning.
마족은 본래 교활하다
With the Sea Calamity approaching,
해운이 다가오는 이때
they will send spies to infiltrate the Central Plains,
마족이 반드시 첩자를 중토에 잠입시켜
spreading confusion and causing trouble.
사람을 현혹하고 몰래 수작을 부릴 것이다
Yangling,
양령
gather the disciples immediately.
즉시 제자를 소집하여
Set up the Demon-Quelling Formation
항마복법진을 배치하라
to secure Wuyue Court.
우리 무월정의 안전을 보장하라
Also,
또한
strictly screen all inner and outer sect disciples.
내외문 제자를 엄중히 조사하고
Strengthen our defenses.
경계를 강화하라
We mustn't give the demons any opening.
결코 마족에게 틈을 주지 말아라
Yes.
예
Master,
사존님
Master Guangwei suspects
광미 사숙께서 의심하시기를
it was a demon spy.
마족 간첩의 소행이라 하셨습니다
He's ordered all peaks to be on high alert against infiltrators.
각 봉에 경계를 명하고 간첩을 막으라 하셨습니다
After all this time,
이렇게 오랜 시간이 지났건만
you still haven't broken through the fifth level.
아직도 제 오 층 공법조차 돌파하지 못하였구나
Useless.
너처럼 쓸모없다면
You probably can't even withstand a single strike from the demons.
아마 마족의 한 번의 공격도 막지 못할 터
How can you lead the sect against the Sea Calamity?
그리해서 어찌 사문을 이끌어 해운을 막을 수 있겠느냐?
How can I possibly
내가 어찌 마음 놓고
entrust Wuyue Court to your hands?
무월정을 네 손에 맡길 수 있겠느냐?
I am deeply ashamed.
제가 부끄럽습니다
Only the strong may remain on Cuihua Peak.
취화봉에는 강자만이 있다
If you show no improvement,
네가 더 이상 발전하지 않으면
step down for the younger disciples.
뒤따르는 사제에게 자리를 내어주도록 하라
Yes.
예
Scatter into wind, gather into form.
흩어져 바람이 되고 모여 형태를 이루며
Draw the essence of heaven and earth,
천지의 기운을 거두어
and fuse the five elemental powers of metal, wood, water, fire, and earth
금목수화토 오행의 힘을
into your vessel.
정에 녹여
Release different techniques according to subtle variations,
미묘한 차이에 따라 선법을 펼치면
and you will have endless transformations.
변화가 끝이 없으니
This is the Earth-Shattering Five Turtles Technique.
이를 석파천경 오귀술이라 하노라
Master! Did you see that?
사부님, 보셨습니까?
I can use the water technique now.
이 수지술을 익혔습니다
Well...
어찌 말할까...
I taught you for so long,
이렇게 오래 가르쳤건만
and you've only just managed to fuse your water and wood spirits.
겨우 너의 수목령을 하나로 융합하였군
I'm a bit ashamed, honestly.
내가 좀 부끄럽다, 정말로
The hard part is still ahead.
어려운 것은 아직 남았다
Especially the metal technique. That's the foremost of the five elements.
특히 금지술은 오행의 으뜸이니
Take your time practicing.
천천히 익혀라
As I always say,
여전히 그 말이다
I've taught you everything.
나는 다 가르쳤고
Whether you succeed is all up to you.
이루고 못 이루는 것은 너 자신에게 달렸다
Where... where did it go?
응? 이게 어찌 사라졌지?
Where did it go?
어찌 사라졌지?
What happened, Master?
이게 무슨 일입니까? 사부님
Take your time practicing.
천천히 익혀라
I'm going back to sleep.
난 돌아가 좀 자야겠다
Practice all you want, but don't forget to cook.
수련은 하되, 밥하는 것을 잊지 말아라
Got it.
알겠습니다
You're still eating while you talk.
사부님 아직도 먹고 있잖습니까?
How am I supposed to use this metal spirit?
이 금령은 도대체 어떻게 사용하는 것이야?
I...
내가
I mastered the metal technique?
내가 금술을 이루었다!
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난도♪
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
What do you want?
대체 무엇을 하려는 거야?
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪Past the pagoda♪
♪거침없이 달리리라♪
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
Your spirit energy.
너의 영기야
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
Take it back.
돌려줄게
Never show your face before me again.
더 이상 내 앞에 나타나지 마
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪It's me, blinded by longing♪
♪내 눈에 병이 생긴 건지♪
♪Every glance lands on you♪
♪눈앞에 온통 너만 가득하네♪
♪Fire and water clash, yet we cling inseparably♪
♪물불은 어울릴 수 없는데 끈끈히 붙어있네♪
♪Lotus broken, threads still bind us♪
♪연은 끊어져도 실은 서로를 잇고♪
♪My heart calm till you stir storms and rain♪
♪내 마음 잔잔한테 넌 비를 내리게 하네♪
♪You are my destined rival♪
♪넌 나의 숙적♪
♪Winters pass, springs come; bound for lifetimes, fate ties me to you♪
♪봄이 오고 생사 함께할 운명은 너에게 달렸네♪
♪Mountains, rivers, lakes and seas, I follow no one but you♪
♪산과 바다를 가리지 않고 너만 따라가리♪
♪Bitterness brews sweet bliss, drained in one sip♪
♪쓴 아픔 속 달콤함을 빚어 마시고♪
♪Love and feud balance out, I'm yours alone♪
♪사랑과 원한을 상쇄하고 너를 마음에 새기네♪
♪Fated foes, fate plays tricks; you complete my five elements♪
♪숙명의 적인데 하늘이 맺어 오행에는 너만 빠졌네♪
♪If you don't leave, I'll never abandon you♪
♪사랑은 뜨겁고 미움은 시원하니 서로 어울리네♪
♪We'll dwell in mortal dust, stay side by side till the end♪
♪이렇게 속세에서 끝까지 함께하리♪
♪Sometimes I throw petty fits♪
♪가끔 투정 부리지♪
♪I blame all troubles on you♪
♪모든 건 네 탓이라며♪
♪Though distant on the surface, our souls resonate as one♪
♪겉은 달라도 마음은 통하는데♪
♪We wander far, parted to separate corners♪
♪각자 먼 길 떠나도♪
♪Yet my heart still leans toward you, my foe♪
♪어쩔 수 없이 마음은 기울고♪
♪I sigh and laugh, defeated in this game of affection♪
♪또 패배한 판을 웃으면 바라보네♪
♪Winters pass, springs come; bound for lifetimes, fate ties me to you♪
♪봄이 오고 생사 함께할 운명은 너에게 달렸네♪
♪Mountains, rivers, lakes and seas, I follow no one but you♪
♪산과 바다를 가리지 않고 너만 따라가리♪
♪Perhaps endless tangling is our silent bond♪
♪아마도 꼬이고 얽히는 것도 궁합인지♪
♪Love and feud balance out, I'm yours alone♪
♪사랑과 원한을 상쇄하고 너를 마음에 새기네♪
♪Fated foes, fate plays tricks; you complete my five elements♪
♪숙명의 적인데 하늘이 맺어 오행에는 너만 빠졌네♪
♪Burning love, unbridled hatred, they suit each other well♪
♪사랑은 뜨겁고 미움은 시원하니 서로 어울리네♪
♪If you don't leave, I'll never abandon you♪
♪네가 떠나지 않는다면 나 또한 포기하지 않으리♪
♪We'll dwell in mortal dust, stay side by side till the end♪
♪이렇게 속세에서 끝까지 함께하리♪